http://www.worldtravelcenter.com/about/privacypolicy/#personalinfo

I. Applicability
This Privacy and Security Notice (the “Notice”) applies to all information gathered or maintained by Senior Market Sales, Inc. (SMS) at TravelInsuranceCenter.com as well as information transmitted to our travel insurance division by telephone, fax, or otherwise by one of our affiliates or agents, and also information received from our call center. Further information about SMS is available at http://www.seniormarketsales.com. Our site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, the security measures, or the content of any such web site.
II. Your Privacy
We recognize that our customers have a need to control the use and management of their personal information. Our goal is to allow you to quickly and easily purchase the insurance products that best fit your needs without jeopardizing your privacy and security in any way. Many of our services are available to you without your entering any personally identifiable information. You can get a quote, learn about our products, use our Policy Picker or receive guidance on what types of policies and products are right for your individual needs. However, because coverage benefits and premiums for insurance policies are affected by your individual traits and circumstances, we may ask you to disclose personally identifiable information when you purchase a plan through our Website, when you have an agent make the purchase for you, or when you phone our call center.
III. How We Collect Information
In order to provide the products and services you request, and for the operation and/or promotion of our business, we may need to collect information from you, including personal information. We collect information from our customers in the following ways:
A. Information You Provide to Us
We may collect information from you directly, such as when you enter it on a web page or web form, when you provide information to one of our agents in person or via phone, or when you include it in an email or other correspondence that you send to us. For example, this type of collection may occur through our profile creation processes, or the use of our comparison tools, where we ask you to provide information such as contact information (e.g. name, email or mailing address, or phone number) or information we need for the creation or administration of your personal profile (e.g. user name, password or security questions). We may also collect information from you directly through our technical and customer support processes, where we may ask you to provide contact information and a description of the issue you are contacting us about.
B. Information Collected Automatically Through our Website
We may also automatically or passively collect information about your use of our website, applications and/or services. While information collected in this manner is not typically personal information, we may combine it in ways that make it personally identifiable. When we do so, we will treat the combined information as personal information. Technologies used in our services to passively collect such information may include:
Cookies. Small data files placed on a device’s hard drive.
Web Beacons. Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons, (also known as “1×1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included on our websites or in our email messages.
Embedded Scripts. Programming code that is temporarily downloaded onto a device, and is active only while you are connected to our website, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.
In addition, our services may use a variety of other hardware or software specific technologies that automatically collect information.
C. Information We Receive From Other Sources
We may also supplement the information that we collect with information that we obtain from other sources. We may combine the information we receive from these outside sources with the information we directly collect. In addition, we may collect information from our trusted external service providers for certain technical data analysis, processing and/or storage offerings.
D. Other Information We Gather from Your Purchase History and Interactions with Us
When you interact with us via phone, text, mail, email, via social media or in person, we may collect transactional or other information about these activities and store it with your personal profile. We may use this information to make predictions about your preferences, interests, and future purchase activity.
IV. Types of Information We Collect
Personal Identifiers.
Information that identifies you or another person, including name, signature, address, date of birth, Social Security number, passport number, telephone and/or fax number, driver’s license or state identification number, gender, and country of citizenship. Personal Identifiers may also include the user identification and password for your Personal Profile on our Website beneficiary name (of life insurance benefits) and relationship of beneficiary.
Commercial Information.
Information including records of your personal property, products or services purchased, obtained or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.
Geolocation Data.
Information that can be used to identify an electronic device's physical location.
Internet or Other Network Activity.
Information including browsing history, search history, and other information regarding your interaction with an internet Website, application or advertisement.
Financial Information.
If you wish to purchase a policy online you will need to provide certain financial information, including the type of credit card you wish to use, the credit card number, and the date of expiration. Final processing of online purchases transpires in one of two ways: 1) credit card payment information is transmitted directly to the designated insurance provider/administrator via SSL-protected secure server communication; 2) credit card payment information is transmitted from our site by encrypted email to the insurance provider where the message is decoded and processed.
Your complete credit card information is stored only by the merchant providing your selected plan(s). We temporarily receive, but do not permanently store, complete credit card information on our server or at our offline site. For security and verification purposes we store the last four digits only of an online purchaser's credit card. The credit card's last four digits are stored with the purchase order(s) with which they are associated and are stored only for use as record locators and to verify purchase orders.
Health Information.
Some insurance plans require you to submit certain personal information concerning your medical history in order to process your request. Health Information includes, but is not limited to, your height, weight, and medical history (for diagnoses of heart condition, anemia, headaches, diabetes, cancer, and other health disorders). SMS does not maintain records of your health information, nor do we make any other use of the information other than to pass it along to the insurer who will provide the policy to you.
If you begin an application for a plan that requires medical information, we will store your application in an encrypted, secure location for two weeks to facilitate completion of the application. If, at the end of two weeks, you have not completed the application or contacted us to keep your file open, that information will be deleted.
We reserve the right to store your health information associated with specific policy applications for our records as necessary as we expand our services in the future.
V. How We Use Your Information
We will use the information you provide to us for the purposes for which you provided the information, as stated at the time of collection, and as otherwise described in this Notice or permitted by law. The following are some of the ways in which we may use your information:
To provide you with the insurance policies and/or protection plans that best meet your unique needs and preferences;
To verify that your purchase orders are received and accurately processed by the appropriate policy producers and/or plan administrators;
To maintain accurate records about who you are and where you learned about us;
To maintain accurate policy records and a personal profile for your secure access via the Web.
To provide you with the insurance policies and/or protection plans that best meet your unique needs and preferences;
Deliver important materials to you pertaining to your selected policies and/or plans.
To communicate with the insurance provider(s) and/or administrator(s) that you have selected and/or to process information for delivery to them;
To contact you in response to your inquiries, comments and suggestions
For our own direct marketing purposes, including distribution of newsletters and/or marketing materials via email.
To improve the products and services we offer to you and develop new products and services;
To improve our Website or mobile applications;
Otherwise with your consent or as required by law.
If you do not wish to receive marketing email from us, or if you decide you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you can remove yourself from our distribution lists at any time by:
You may update and edit your Personal Profile at any time by going to the My Policies section of the site and clicking on Edit Your Personal Profile. Your edited changes will take effect immediately upon submission. You can also use this feature to change your password, should you so desire. If you want us to remove all of your personal information from our active database, email us at privacy@seniormarketsales.com or write to the address listed above and include your user ID and phone number along with the request to no longer have an active Personal Profile. You may also remove the information yourself by accessing your Personal Profile and entering blank spaces in the data fields.
Opting Out of Marketing Emails or Newsletters:
Simply replying and inserting the word "remove" in the subject field to any marketing email you receive.
Logging on to our site and changing the boxes in your Personal Profile to indicate that you do not wish to receive the newsletter and/or marketing materials
Sending an email request for removal to privacy@seniormarketsales.com.
Writing to us at SMS Attn: Privacy Officer, 8420 West Dodge Road, Suite 510, Omaha NE 68114 USA.
Updating your Personal Profile and Password:
VI. How We Share Your Information with Third Parties
Consistent with this Notice and applicable law, we may share the information you share with us with affiliated and non-affiliated third parties as follows:
The insurance companies and plan administrators who administer the product, plan or service you request;
Our corporate affiliates;
Third Party Service Providers – Third parties that provide us with services, including but not limited to data hosting and/or other services that allow us to provide you with the products and services you request;
Third Party Joint Marketing Partners – Third parties with whom we have joint marketing or similar contractual agreements to provide you with marketing and promotional offers;
Government, legal or regulatory authorities, or others, but only when required to do so by law or in response to a subpoena, court order, or other valid legal process.
If you would like us to stop providing your information to Joint Marketing Partners or to our corporate affiliates for marketing purposes, please contact privacy@seniormarketsales.com.
Opting Out of Affiliate and/or Third Party Marketing
VII. Privacy Rights for California Residents
Consistent with California’s “Shine the Light” law (Cal. Civ. Code 1798.83), we provide California residents with the ability to “opt out” of having their personal information shared with affiliates and non-affiliated third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, you may opt-out of having your personal information shared with affiliated and non-affiliated third parties for their direct marketing purposes by following the opt-out instructions in Section XI below.
Effective January 1, 2020, the California Consumer Privacy Act (the “CCPA”) provides California residents with new privacy protections and rights regarding their personal information. This Privacy and Security Notice has been revised to include a description of those rights and other information required to be disclosed under the CCPA. This section is applicable only to customers who are residents of California, as that term is defined by the CCPA and other California privacy laws (together “California Laws”).
If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Notice, our practices, and/or your rights under California Laws, please contact us at privacy@seniormarketsales.com or (800)786-5566, extension 4567.
Information You Provide Directly to Us
(described in Paragraph III-A)
Categories of Information
Personal identifiers; legally protected characteristics1; commercial information; biometric information2; professional or employment information
Purposes for Collection
To provide the services you request; to recommend services that best meet your unique needs and preferences; to verify that contracting and appointment requests are received and accurately processed by the appropriate policy producers and/or plan administrators; to maintain accurate records and a personal profile for your secure access to our websites and tools; to deliver important materials to you pertaining to insurance providers with whom you do business and products you may offer to your clients; to operate incentives or contests;to contact you and/or your designated contacts directly, should the need arise.
Types of Third Parties with Whom We Share
Third Party Service Providers; Third Party Joint Marketing Partners; governmental bodies (i.e. in response to a subpoena or regulatory request)
1. Characteristics of protective classifications under California or federal law (for example, race, national origin, religion or creed, physical or mental disability, etc.)
2. Under the CCPA, “Biometric Information” means an individual’s physiological, biological or behavioral characteristics, including an individual’s deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA), that can be used, singly or in combination with each other or with other identifying data, to establish individual identity. Biometric information includes, but is not limited to, imagery of the iris, retina, fingerprint, face, hand, palm, vein patterns, and voice recordings, from which an identifier template, such as a faceprint, a minutiae template, or a voiceprint, can be extracted, and keystroke patterns or rhythms, gait patterns or rhythms, and sleep, health, or exercise data that contain identifying information
Information Automatically Collected Through our Website (described in Paragraph III-B)
Categories of Information
Personal identifiers; internet or other similar network activity; geolocation data; inferences drawn from personal information.
Purposes for Collection
To provide the services you request; to improve our products, services, Websites or mobile applications; to track your use of our Websites; to create and update customer profiles; for internal market research and analytics.
Types of Third Parties with Whom We Share
Third party Service Providers; Third Party Joint Marketing Partners; digital advertising providers.
Information We Receive From Other Sources
(described in Paragraph III-C)
Categories of Information
Personal identifiers; legally protected characteristics; commercial information; geolocation data; professional or employment information.
Purposes for Collection
To improve our products, services, Websites or mobile applications; to provide services; to track your use of our Websites; to create and update customer profiles; for internal market research and analytics; to maintain accurate policy records and a personal profile for your secure access via the Web; to deliver important materials to you pertaining to your selected policies or plans; to contact you and/or your designated contacts directly, should the need arise.
Types of Third Parties with Whom we Share
Third Party Service Providers; Third Party Joint Marketing Partners; governmental bodies (i.e. in response to a subpoena or regulatory request)
Other Information We Gather from Your Purchase History and Interactions with Us (described in Paragraph III-D)
Categories of Information
Personal identifiers; commercial information; inferences drawn from personal information.
Purposes for Collection
To improve our products, services, Websites and mobile applications; to track your use of our Websites and services; to create and update customer profiles; to notify you of information or offers that may be of interest to you; to predict your preferences, interests and future purchases.
Types of Third Parties with Whom we Share
Third Party Service Providers; Third Party Joint Marketing Partners; governmental bodies (i.e. in response to a subpoena or regulatory request).
Under California Laws, California residents can exercise the following rights: (a) to Disclosure and Access; (b) to Deletion of their Personal Information; and (c) to Opt Out of the “Sale” of Personal Information. Each of these rights are described in more detail in Sections IX, X and XI below (collectively “Rights”). These Rights are not absolute and are subject to certain exceptions under the law. For instance, we are not required to delete personal information which is required to provide a service that has been requested by you.
You may exercise your rights under CCPA through an Authorized Agent that is designated according to our procedures. Please email us at privacy@seniormarketsales.com for additional information.
California residents also have a right not to be discriminated against for the exercise of their Rights. This means, among other things, that we cannot charge you different prices for services or impose penalties on you because you exercise your rights under CCPA. Certain financial incentive programs may be allowed under the CCPA, if the incentives are reasonably related to the value of customer data.
If you are a California resident, we will process your request to exercise your Rights in accordance with California Laws. When a request is made, we may first take steps to verify your identity to protect your privacy and security. Please contact privacy@seniormarketsales.com for more information regarding identity verification requirements. Further, if you designate an Authorized Agent to make a request on your behalf (as described in Paragraph VII-B), you may have to submit information confirming that designation. Subject to California Laws, we will not act upon a request until your identity has been sufficiently verified.
We may maintain a record concerning the requests to fulfill our legal obligations. Further, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to act on a request if the request is excessive, repetitive or manifestly unfounded.
Information we collect.
Rights of California Residents.
Verification and Recordkeeping.
VIII. Disclosure and Access Requests
California consumers have the right to request that we disclose to them, for the twelve (12) month period preceding the date of the request: (i) the categories of personal information we have collected about them; (ii) the categories of sources from which personal information is collected; (iii) the business or commercial purpose for the information collection; (iv) the categories of third parties with whom we have shared personal information; and (v) the specific pieces of personal information we hold about an individual. Please note that we are only required to fulfill disclosure and access requests from a consumer twice during any twelve (12) month period.
California consumers can make a disclosure and access request, subject to the exceptions in the CCPA, by contacting our privacy team at (800) 786-5566, extension 4567, or by emailing privacy@seniormarketsales.com.
IX. Deletion Requests
California consumers have the right to have their personal information deleted, subject to certain exceptions (for example, to comply with legal obligations, complete transactions or for our certain internal uses). In the course of fulfilling a valid deletion request, we will also endeavor to direct our service providers to delete your personal information from their records.
California residents can make a personal information deletion request, subject to the exceptions in the CCPA by contacting our privacy team at (800) 786-5566, extension 4567, or by emailing privacy@seniormarketsales.com.
X. Opting Out of the Sale of Personal Information
California and Nevada consumers have the right to opt-out of having their personal information sold. Under the CCPA, the definition of “sale” includes a typical sale (i.e., a transfer of data from a seller to a buyer in exchange for money), but it also includes sharing of personal information with a third party in exchange for anything of value (money or otherwise).
California residents and Nevada residents can opt out from having personal information “sold” to third parties, subject to the limitations of California Laws and Nevada Law, by clicking on the “Do Not Sell My Information” link on our homepage and submitting this Opt-Out Web Form, or by contacting our privacy team by phone at (800) 786-5566, extension 4567, or by emailing privacy@seniormarketsales.com.
Subject to applicable law, opting out through this mechanism will not prevent your personal information from being shared with third parties for non-marketing purposes (for example, to process one of your transactions). Further, this opt out mechanism will not prevent the transfer of personal information in connection with a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of our assets.
We do not sell the personal information of minors under sixteen (16) years of age.
XI. Security
All of the information that you transmit to us electronically, via phone, or through one of our agents, including personally identifiable information disclosed during registration as well as credit card and other personally identifiable information provided during the online purchase process, is securely protected using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) 128-bit encryption. VeriSign, the world's leading provider of Internet trust services, provides the digital certificate enabling us to employ SSL encryption. (Some users, such as those accessing our site from outside the USA, may employ browsers that only support a lower level of SSL, such as 40-bit encryption). Furthermore, we have implemented strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your personally identifiable financial information from unauthorized access or improper use, and we will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available.
XII. What are Your Children's Guidelines?
We do not knowingly collect online contact information or personally identifiable offline contact information about children from children.
We do not entice children by the prospect of a special game, prize or activity, to divulge any information about themselves for any reason. We do not permit children under the age of thirteen (13) to register with our sites, as we do not knowingly accept or store personally identifiable information submitted by children younger than thirteen, nor do we respond to, promote to, market to, or communicate with children known to be younger than thirteen years old.
However, some personally identifiable information about children must be disclosed by parents or guardians or their designated agents when such persons are engaged in the process of making online purchases of insurance and/or travel assistance plans intended to cover and/or apply to said children. In the event that we receive any personally identifiable information about children under the age of sixteen (16), we will not share the information with any party other than the insurance company to whom the application is directed, and will only use that information for the specific purpose of fulfilling the service, plan or policy request of the parent, guardian or designated agent.
XIII. Changes to Our Privacy and Security Notice
We reserve the right to amend this Privacy and Security Notice at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this Notice, we will post the updated notice on this Site and update the Notice’s effective date. Your continued use of our web site following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.
XIII. Contact Information
Questions regarding this Notice, or the ways in which we collect, use, or share your information, or if you wish to exercise your rights under California or any other state law, please do not hesitate to contact us by email at:
privacy@seniormarketsales.com
Or by writing to:
SMS – Attention: TIC Privacy Policy
8420 W. Dodge Rd. Suite 500
Omaha, NE 68114
Or call us at:
(800)786-5566 extension 4567
The Travel Insurance Experts™
User Feedback
Close
